<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Book Sum</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Android Studio</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">android.studio@android.com</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="str2">
    <ul>
        <li>Lists out all your favourite genres</li>
        <li>Best books from your favourite genre</li>
        <li>Summaries of the books included to save time searching them individually</li>
    </ul>
</string>

    <string name="menu_home">Home</string>
    <string name="menu_gallery">Gallery</string>
    <string name="menu_slideshow">Slideshow</string>
    <!-- href tag is used to add link-->
    <!-- link for home text view-->
    <string name="hyperlink0"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/pranav-sreenath/">S. Pranav</a></string>
    <string name="hyperlink1"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/aniket-khajanchi/">Aniket Khajanchi</a></string>
    <string name="hyperlink2"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/karan-jangir-7927241ba/">Karan Jangir</a></string>
    <string name="hyperlink3"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/itsnitish22/">Nitish Sharma</a></string>
    <!-- link for practice textview-->
    <string name="title_activity_the_hard_things">The Hard Things About Hard things </string>
    <string name="large_text">
        Building a Business When There Are No Easy Answers
Ben Horowitz is the cofounder of Andreessen Horowitz (A16Z) and one of Silicon Valley’s most respected and experienced entrepreneurs. In ‘The Hard Thing about Hard Things’ he shares his experience of being a founder-CEO and the hard decisions he has had to make — offering advice on managing tough problems as a leader, which business schools do not cover. While most management books focus on doing things correctly, Ben offers insights into what you must do after you have screwed up.
Horowitz was exposed to a diverse perspective from a very early age; parents indoctrinated in the Communist philosophy, grandparents were card-carrying Communists and at Berkeley High School football team, he was the only player to excel academically. Looking at the world through different perspectives helped him learn how to separate facts from perceptions. This ability proved incredibly useful when he became an entrepreneur, especially in dire circumstances when looking at alternative narratives and radically different perspectives kept him informed.
Horowitz founded a company called LoudCloud in 1999, based on the emerging concept of a computing cloud. "\n \n"
In spite of the challenges, Horowitz firmly believed in “Treating your employees fairly and always telling them the truth.” He understood that figuring out the right product is the innovator’s job, not the customer’s and after the first line of code is written, decisions are no longer objective in the technology business.
        "\n \n"

When the odds of LoudCloud’s survival were low, Ben’s friend and LoudCloud board member, Bill Campbell advised him to prepare for bankruptcy, but he never made such a contingency plan. He believed that CEOs should not play the odds. When you are building a company, you must believe there is an answer, and you cannot pay attention to the odds of finding it. You just have to find it. It matters not whether your chances are nine in ten or one in a thousand; the task is the same.
There is no secret to being a successful CEO he states; however, the ability to focus and make the best move when there seems to be no good moves is crucial. When things get unbearably difficult, and the struggle begins, there are a few things you can try. "\n \n"
Second, CEO’s Should Tell It Like It Is and ensure informal information and ideas are flowing freely in your company, instead of adopting the old management standard: “Don’t bring me a problem without bringing me a solution.” What if the employee cannot solve an important problem?
Thirdly — and this is a tough one — you will have to lay people off at some point. Hence, get your head right by focusing on the future of the company rather than the past. Do not delay. If word leaks out before you execute the decision, a whole new set of issues will arise. Be clear about why you need to lay people off. If it is because the company failed to hit its plan, then admit that failure. Then be visible and present, to boost the confidence of those who are still on board.
So, what’s the secret to being a “successful” CEO? Sadly, none, Ben says, other than making the best move when there are no good moves. "\n \n"
Hororwitz puts forward the idea that there is a significant difference between a Peacetime CEO vs. a Wartime CEO, which sparks great interest. Let me quote directly from the book:
According to Horowitz, it is crucial to create a good work environment. It’s important that the people who spend most of their waking life at work have a good environment to exist in while there. Being a good company doesn’t matter when things go well, but it can be the difference between life and death when things go wrong.When things go well, there are many reasons to stay at a company —
1. Your career grows as the company grows, attractive jobs naturally open up
2. You’ll be impressing your friends and family. Your friends and family will think you a genius for choosing to work at the “it” company
3. Your résumé gets stronger by working at a blue-chip company in its heyday.
4. Oh, and you are getting rich."\n \n"
However, when things go poorly, all those reasons evaporate and become reasons to leave. In fact, the only thing that keeps an employee at a company when things go horribly wrong — other than needing a job — is that she likes her job, despite the hardships
So on that note the book advises when expanding your team, consider:
1. Hire for strength rather than lack of weakness.
2. Have clear expectations of who you are hiring with a realization that there is something seriously wrong with every employee in your company (including you). Nobody is perfect.
3. Involve multiple people in brainstorming but make the final decision solo. Consensus-based decisions tend to sway the process away from strength and towards weakness.
Especially when hiring executives, it is very important to remember that being a big company executive is very different from being a small company executive. Big company executives are driven by interruptions, while startup executives know that nothing happens unless they make it happen. A big company executive has an incredible number of incoming demands on his time, whereas in a small company without a massive push, the company will stay at rest. "\n \n"

I think Horowitz is quite correct when he states in this chapter that most workplaces are far from good. As organizations grow larger, important work can go unnoticed. The hardest workers can get passed over in favor of the best office politicians, and bureaucratic processes can choke out the creativity and true productivity.
As a company grows, Horowitz says, it is important to minimize politics within your organization. One of the biggest issues behind politics is when people advance their own careers or their personal agendas instead of merit or contribution.
Here are the four takeaways for minimizing politics in the company. "\n \n"
Firstly, hire people with the right kind of ambition; otherwise, your company would turn into the political equivalent of the U.S Senate. The right kind is ambition for the company’s success; with the executive’s own success coming on only as a by-product.
Secondly, maintain strict policies and processes on organizational design, performance evaluations, promotions, and compensation
Thirdly, you should promote experienced employees by measuring results against objectives, management skills, innovation, and their ability to work well with others.
Fourthly, ensure one-on-one meetings between employees and managers. These are an excellent platform for employees to discuss their as yet unheard brilliant ideas, pressing issues, and chronic frustrations. "\n \n"

Every CEO, Horowitz writes, of a startup should focus on what needs to be right rather than worrying about what is wrong. One of the most difficult challenges is keeping your mind in check. You need to be able to move aggressively and decisively without acting insane. To calm your nerves, find someone you can talk to who understands what you’re going through. Put your ideas, challenges, and fears on paper for a better focus on where you are going and not what you are trying to avoid.
There is a fine Line Between Fear and Courage — People who watch you judge you on what you do, not how you feel. "\n \n"

Reiterating a theme that comes up again and again in the book as a whole this chapter is devoted to the idea that there are no rules in business. Things may seem to be going well, but they can change in an instant. You need accountability and creativity to succeed in business. Accountability is the key for effort, promises and results.
The hard things will always be hard; courage and grit are the keys to success."\n \n"

Continuing his personal story Horowitz recalls that after selling Opsware, he went to work for Hewlett-Packard, but he still knew he wanted to do something else. He decided to set up a firm designed to help technical founders run their companies. Technical founders are the best people to run technology companies. All long-lasting technologies thrived when led by their innovator ; Intel, Amazon, Apple, Google and Facebook had been run by their founders and in some cases still are to this day
With this new company Horowitz wanted to imapart to founders that things are hard because there are no easy answers or recipes. They are hard because your emotions are at odds with your logic. They are hard because you don’t know the answer and you cannot ask for help without showing weakness. While his firm cannot give a founder CEO all the skills he or she needs, it can provide mentorship based on his experience and learnings.
Summary. "\n \n"

While most start-up stories may read like a romance novel, this tome is more like watching the film “Fight Club”. The writing has a biting, sarcastic, blunt humor and uses hip-hop lyrics as intros to chapters. It’s fun and entertaining to read but most of all it’s an amazing insider look into the world of tech and how to succeed in this unique industry.
If you are leading a team of any size there is much more to be learned from “The Hard Thing About Hard Things’ and so I would strongly recommend getting and reading a copy for yourself. "\n \n"
    </string>
</resources>